Our app will be a game based off the of 3D chess.
All chess pieces retain their movement along the X, Y, and Z axis.
For example, a pawn can move up one Y, along one x, or down one Z.
It can only capture a piece diagonally, as usual, but said piece can be diagonal up a Y.
The chess 'board' would be 5x5x5, set vertically.
In the GUI, I'm visualizing the chess boards levels (Alpha-Epsilon) being toggleable, using some sort of button or toggle to move between each board level.
A timer will also be included, as per the traditional chess fashion though it will be optional, and logic rules will have to be made for the individual pieces, as well as space conflict avoidance (so friendly pieces cannot move on top of eachother), capture rules, and rules for checkmate.

List of goals:
□ basic gui -- chessboard
□ pieces loaded
□ pieces moveable
□ capture mechanics
□ checkmate
□ no friendly fire
□ turn/total timer
□ "window dressing" -- menu, options, etc.
□ save game
□ graphics
□ additional options (sound, )